Raja Ravi Varma Collection
Raja Ravi Varma Collection
2005-2007
1.5 linear ft.
Noted Indian painter. Prints, audiovisual material, exhibit material.
5135322
Biographical History
Raja Ravi Varma (1848-1906) was a celebrated Indian painter and artist. He is particularly noted for his works featuring Hindu goddesses and scenes from the Mahabharata. These prints come from the collection of Om Prakash, a retired engineer with the Indian Central Government and avid collector.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Raja Ravi Varma Collection consists of prints and material relating to several exhibits of Prakash's collection, including a permanent exhibit at Baroda Heritage Art Gallery in Baroda City. The collection also has several DVDs with content related to Varma, including a 2007 prize-winning documentary.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type.
Related Material
See also the
Indian Religious Posters Collection
and the
Daniel Smith Poster Archive
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Painters; Religion and Philosophy; Ravi Varma, 1848-1906.; Baroda Heritage Art Gallery and Museum.; When the brush dropped.; Hindu gods -- Posters.; Popular culture -- India.; Popular culture -- Religious aspects -- India.; Hindu gods in art.; Hindu symbolism -- Specimens.; Hinduism.; Exhibit scripts.; Posters.; Lithographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Shipping information bears the name of Om Prakash and of Baroda Art Gallery.
Inventory
- Audiovisual material
  - Raja Ravi Varma / Before the Brush Dropped [copy 1], 2007; raj_rav_var_001; documentary about Indian painter Raja Ravi Varma; film received Best Documentary in the Kerala State Film Awards. File format .vcd; 1 DVD (Oversize 1)
  - Raja Ravi Varma / Before the Brush Dropped [copy 2], 2007; raj_rav_var_002; documentary about Indian painter Raja Ravi Varma; film received Best Documentary in the Kerala State Film Awards. File format .vcd; 1 DVD (Oversize 1)
  - Raja Ravi Varma / Oleographs / E-Books [copy 1], [2005?]; raj_rav_var_003; photos from Mysore exhibit, slide shows, video clips, ebooks. File formats .exe, .ppt, .jpg, .mpg, .doc; 1 DVD (Oversize 1)
  - Raja Ravi Varma / Oleographs / E-Books [copy 2], [2005?]; raj_rav_var_004; photos from Mysore exhibit, slide shows, video clips, ebooks. File formats .exe, .ppt, .jpg, .mpg, .doc; 1 DVD (Oversize 1)
  - Raja Ravi Varma / The Painter Prince [copy 1], raj_rav_var_005; .vcd, content unknown; 1 DVD (Oversize 1)
  - Raja Ravi Varma / The Painter Prince [copy 2], raj_rav_var_006; .vcd, content unknown; DVD broken in half; 1 DVD (Oversize 1)
- Exhibit material
  - Miscellaneous, 2005; promotional items, facsimile of news article, exhibit text, etc. from exhibits in Delhi, Mysore, and Baroda City (Oversize 1)
- Prints
  - Assorted prints, encapsulated, 12 items (Oversize 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Photocopy of page from auction house, sheets with thumbnails of Varma Press prints (Oversize 1)